They only met once, but it changed their lives forever.
The Breakfast Club is a comedy, drama film directed by John Hughes.
Five high school students from different walks of life endure a
Saturday detention under a power-hungry principal.
The disparate group includes rebel John, princess Claire,
outcast Allison, brainy Brian and Andrew, the jock.
Each has a chance to tell his or her story, making the others see them a little differently
-- and when the day ends, they question whether school will ever be the same.
Andrew Clark, played by Emilio Estevez.
John Bender, played by Judd Nelson.
Claire Standish, played by Molly Ringwald.
Brian Johnson, played by Anthony Michael Hall.
Allison Reynolds, played by Ally Sheedy.
Richard Vernon, played by Paul Gleason.
The Breakfast Club is a 1985 American coming-of-age comedy-drama
film written, produced, and directed by John Hughes.
It stars Emilio Estevez, Paul Gleason, Anthony Michael Hall,
Judd Nelson, Molly Ringwald, and Ally Sheedy.
The film tells the story of five teenagers from different high school cliques who serve
a Saturday detention overseen by their authoritarian Vice Principal.
Hughes had written the script in 1982, and began casting for the
film after the release of Sixteen Candles (1984).
Filming took place from March to May 1984, and the entire film was shot
at Maine North High School in Des Plaines, Illinois.
Although the film is technically not an independent film due to Universal Pictures' involvement as a producer, The Breakfast Club has been popularly recognized
as one; the low budget, Universal not being the primary production company, and the overall feel of the film are factors to its recognition.
The film premiered in Los Angeles on February 7, 1985, and was
theatrically released by Universal Pictures on February 15, 1985.
It grossed $51.5 million against a $1 million budget, and earned acclaim from critics,
who consider it to be one of Hughes's most memorable and recognized works.
The media subsequently referred to the film's five main actors
as members of a group called the "Brat Pack".
In 2015, the film was digitally remastered and was re-screened in
430 theaters in celebration of its 30th anniversary.
In 2016, The Breakfast Club was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by
the Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film has been considered as one of the best films of the
1980s, and one of the best teen films of all time.
The film explores themes of high school, coming of age,
teen angst, detention, teenage rebellion.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.